All right, fire away.
>> All right, Ben, quick question for you.
The rookies came on late in the season,
Luther, Coulson Lovelin. What can you do
for them heading into year two? What can
they do in the offseason to make
themselves into superstars in this team,
you know, take this team to the Super
Bowl next year?
>> Yeah. So, uh, I mean, that's the good
news about going into year two is you
got a much better feel for the players
on the roster and and certainly the two
guys that you mentioned are are, uh,
guys that we look to target in the draft
last year and they're going to be a big
part of what we're doing going forward.
Uh, neither one of them had a full off
season with us because they were both
coming off some some injuries. you know,
uh, Coulson had one during the season
and then Luther got dinged up a little
bit as as we were training in the
spring, but, uh, you know, we we look
forward to getting them through a full
offseason program and seeing where it
goes from there.
>> Is there anything else that you can take
from last year's draft process to go
into this year?
>> Uh, no, we got a vision. Uh Ryan does a
great job of of stacking that board, him
and his crew, and was able to sit in
with some of the the scouts earlier. And
uh I think they they do a great job
bringing the information to the table
and and we we'll proceed business as
usual.
part of it.
>> Yeah, I I think that's a challenging
thing because uh like I said, it's
completely different than a year ago
where you're coming in with a blank
slate. You really don't know the
personalities and and you haven't really
uh you appreciate them as what they put
on tape, but not so much for uh how they
interact day in and day out in the
building. And so there there's certainly
relationships that are formed. Um I I'll
say that this is one of the closest knit
groups I've ever been a part of last
year's team. And that's that's hard to
generate. I wish there was some magic
stick that you could just float on out
there to to make that happen. And yet um
you know we had a lot of high character
players that they came together and they
they wanted what was best for the team
and and for their buddies. And so, um,
you know, that's it's a hard thing to
replicate, as I mentioned, but, uh, we
have to do what's best for the team. And
as we stack back up the 90man roster
again, uh, we got numerous holes to fill
and I know Ryan and I are committed to
to making it the most competitive roster
we can.
>> Yeah, I we've got some we got some
opportunities there. uh whether it's
free agency or the draft and uh
certainly some of our own in the
building as well that we're we're
looking to continue to develop. And so
um we we look at all the all the
opportunities out there and uh we we've
got a lot of conversations going on for
what that's going to look like. Uh and
it's not just that one position. It's
it's really a lot of them. We we have a
lot of uh guys currently that are free
agents that um we got to make some tough
decisions on and if we can't bring them
back and like I told them at the uh the
last meeting, I wish we could bring
everyone back, but that's just not how
it works. And so if we can't bring them
back, then uh we certainly have to look
to fill that void somehow.
>> Ben, you've openly said that you're
going back to square one this off
season, even after winning the division
for the first time in seven years. Uh
what does that look like for you guys?
Um especially through the draft process.
Yeah. Yeah. Um, you know, each each
phase of the offseason kind of brings
its own challenges. So, right now we we
evaluated our own roster. Um, I think
our our coaching staff has done a
fantastic job evaluating the free agents
that are out there. Um, and now now
we're starting to dive into the draft
guys. And so, uh, you know, it doesn't
really change anything from from our
process or our procedure, but it's
always exciting this time of year. And
and I know our crew is going to do a
great job with that evaluation.
right now in terms of like 12 and 13
personnel wrestling. What do you like
about that as a coach and how do you
think that impacts draft?
>> Yeah. No, I think over the over uh you
know I've been 14 years now in this
league and you've certainly seen more 11
personnel on first and second down uh
over those 14 years. And so what has
happened is rather than base defense
being the primary defense for most
defenses, it's it's now nickel defense
or some variation of that. And so um you
know there's always a ying and a yang to
it. And and because of that, I think a
lot of teams now install nickel defenses
their their day one install and they
have a lot more defense and they give
offenses a lot more problems out of
that. And so, um, naturally, I think
offenses have tried to counter that by
getting them back into base defense by
going heavier. Um, sometimes 12
personnel will do the trick, other times
13 will do the trick. But, um, I do
think having some some versatility at
that tight end position, that's that's
hard to find. Um, we certainly are very
fortunate to have a roster full of of
some really good players that we feel
good about blocking in line to lining
out wide as a receiver to being back in
the back field. And so when you have
that versatility, it really opens up
Pandora's box.
>> H what does that say about the ability
of guys?
>> Yeah. No, I think uh it's certainly
different than what it used to be when I
first joined the NFL. and uh you know
some of the some of the older veteran
coaches have have kind of I don't want
to say faded away but they've stepped to
the side a little bit and it's been a
little bit younger. I think you've seen
the age of offensive coordinators or
play callers go down over the course of
the last 20 years or so. And uh I think
teams have kind of seen this model of
where if you can make your play caller
the head coach then you can have
continuity with your quarterback for an
extended period of time which is which
is a valuable thing. the uh the play
callers that that are not head coaches,
they tend to get plucked pretty quickly
to become head coaches of their own and
it kind of leaves the previous team in
limbo to to figure out the next course
of action.
>> Drew doesn't need my advice. Drew Drew
does a great job. Um he's he's a dear
friend of mine and and I know he's going
to knock knock it out of the park there
in Detroit. And so uh very very happy
for him and that opportunity. There's a
ton of really good players there.
There's um some some coaches in that
building that I care deeply for and so I
I think they're in good hands.
>> Talk about young coaches from your first
year as a coach. What did you learn
about the talent?
>> Yeah. Uh no, I mean you got to do
whatever it takes to get the job done.
And so each each uh each day is kind of
its own story that way. But, um, you
know, it's I'm not going to get
specifics to how long I was in the
office or anything like that, but we got
a great staff and we're all committed to
getting getting, uh, whatever works done
that's necessary, but at the same time,
we do need to bring energy in for the
players each each and every day as well.
>> Oh, uh, we'll miss a ton. Uh the guy's a
phenomenal football coach and you know
that that coaching staff a year ago and
and really similar to this year is there
were a lot of guys outside of my circle
that I didn't know very well. So he was
really through reputation. Uh we had a
lot of productive conversations before
he decided to join on board. Then I was
just blown away from the impact he had
not only in that position room which um
you know Swift had probably the best
year of his career and then seventh
rounder. Manungai had a hell of a year
himself. Um not just that room but the
entire offense he he brings a a
demanding presence. Um the standard is
the standard with Eric Benemy and uh you
know that's those are big shoes to fill.
Um, fortunately I do feel strongly about
Eric Studsville from from Miami. Um, a
guy that I worked with before. Uh, he's
been around the block a few times. He's
been a part of really good rushing
offenses in his past and and I know he's
going to bring a great flavor for us.
>> Uh, yeah. Well, I think last year was
pretty much uh an audition as far as I'm
concerned. I I was blown away with what
he was able to do uh in the building day
in and day out. things that maybe not
everyone else could see. Um he's very
thoughtful, very detail oriented. Um for
what we were looking for from that role,
he he really fits the bill perfectly.
>> No, no,
no. Um
I love I love Tyson. Um, and that's one
that that kind of pulls at your
heartstrings a little bit because
because he's someone that you you care
about so deeply and he's a hell of a
football player that uh at some point
you want to see him have a chance to to
do it himself. And uh and so, you know,
we'll always do what's best for for our
team and our organization. Um, I do
think there's a lot of uh merit to
having a strong number two quarterback,
which he certainly fits that bill. I'm
I'm of the mind that he's probably one
of the best 32 in the NFL. Um, his
preseason tape over the last few years
is probably um confirmed that in my
opinion. Um, but self, you know, if I
took myself out of the equation, you
know, I I want what's best for him. if
he uh if he would like an opportunity to
start. I I I certainly hope he can get
that somewhere.
>> You look at this off seasonal offense
like you might have some expendable
pieces in that group
just trying to free up maybe not having
as many top tier receivers.
>> Well, you can never have too much
talent. I mean, that's uh I I know what
you're getting at there, Courtney, but I
feel I feel really good about the
players that we have. And like I said,
we we've got such a better feel as a
staff now than what we did um when we
started a year ago. And so each guy
brings something different to the table.
Um and and that's really what we're
looking to generate from all of our
skill positions. How can we best
complement each other? Who's got the
speed? Who we need versatility? Guys
that can line up all over the place. Um
certainly guys that have great hands. Um
but uh yeah, I I I think when you look
at a 17 game season or 17 game plus when
you make the postseason, you you need
all hands on deck because the the truth
of the matter is not everybody is going
to going to stay available throughout
that duration.
>> Seems it seems like a true scenario.
How come you think nobody's been
>> uh I Yeah, I I I don't know that so
much. Um, you know, we're just really
focused on on building the best roster
we can right now to to be honest with
you.
>> Dennis Allen, uh, how much of a
challenger do you see it to retool this
defensive side of the ball and how big
of a voice are you about specific
players, you know, and trying to def
>> Yeah. Well, I I think we feel uh we feel
a lot better about having the health of
our secondary u be a lot better this go
around. you know, last year between
Kyler and Jaylen, we didn't feel like we
were at full strength there on the back
end for majority of the season. I I do
think that's going to help out. Um I
think there's ways that we can generate
more pass rush up front that that'll
help out significantly as well. Um but
certainly it's it's something we're
looking at. How do we upgrade the
personnel in certain spots? Um, there's
a number of guys that are up
contractwise and so there there will be
a retooling there to a degree, but I
know DA uh is looking forward to the
opportunity to to get his hands on these
guys one more time and uh and see what
that looks like.
>> Say it again.
>> Yeah. No, I Declan's a phenomenal
football coach. um if if you didn't know
that he was 29 years old, you wouldn't
blink an eye. I mean, the guy is season
beyond his years, this this has been his
calling. He's he's known for a long time
that he was going to be a football coach
and he's prepared himself accordingly.
Um very detail oriented. Um extremely
smart, has a great way to communicating.
He's very clear. Um so I think those
guys are getting getting someone really
really good. You know, I'm disappointed
that that we lost them as as quickly as
we did. I was hoping that we'd be able
to hold on to him for longer.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You know, my experience with
Blau has been as a as a player, but uh
you could kind of tell early on that he
was that coaching was going to be in his
calling as well. Um he's he's got a
unique ability to relate with those guys
and it doesn't matter what position it
is, those guys, they all rally to him.
um that they he certainly did that when
he was a player. Um he elevates the
people around him and I think that's
always the biggest compliment you you
can give somebody.
Good. Thank you. Definitely.